So today, I want us to reflect
إذن اليوم، أريد منا أن نفكر
on the demise of guys.
في نهاية الرجال.
Guys are flaming out academically;
الرجال يخفقون أكاديميا؛
they're wiping out socially with girls
إنهم ينهزمون إجتماعيا مع البنات
and sexually with women.
وجنسيا مع النساء.
Other than that, there's not much of a problem.
ما عدا ذلك، ليس هناك مشكلة تذكر.
So what's the data?
إذن ما هي البيانات؟
So the data on dropping out is amazing.
إذن فبيانات الإنقطاع عن الدراسة مذهلة.
Boys are 30 percent more likely than girls
الأولاد أكثر عرضة بنسبة 30 في المئة من البنات
to drop out of school.
للإنقطاع عن الدراسة.
In Canada, five boys drop out for every three girls.
في كندا، 5 أولاد ينقطعون مقابل 3 بنات.
Girls outperform boys now at every level,
والآن البنات يتفوقن على الأولاد في كل مستوى،
from elementary school to graduate school.
من المدرسة الإبتدائية إلى المدرسة العليا.
There's a 10 percent differential
هناك فارق 10 بالمئة
between getting BA's and all graduate programs,
في الحصول على درجة البكالوريوس وجميع البرامج العليا،
with guys falling behind girls.
بتقدم البنات على الأولاد.
Two-thirds of all students in special ed. remedial programs are guys.
ثلثا الطلبة في البرامج الإصلاحية الخاصة ذكور.
And as you all know,
وكما تعرفون جميعا،
boys are five times more likely than girls
الأولاد هم خمس مرات أكثر عرضة من البنات
to be labeled as having attention deficit disorder --
لأن يُشخصوا بمرض اضطراب نقص الإنتباه --
and therefore we drug them with Ritalin.
وبالتالي نصف لهم عقار الريتالين.
What's the evidence of wiping out?
ما هو الدليل على الانهزام؟
First, it's a new fear of intimacy.
أولا، إنه خوف جديد من الألفة.
Intimacy means physical, emotional connection
الألفة تعني العلاقة المادية والعاطفية
with somebody else --
مع شخص آخر --
and especially with somebody of the opposite sex
وبالخصوص مع شخص من جنس آخر
who gives off ambiguous, contradictory,
يصدر إشارات فسفورية
phosphorescent signals.
غامضة ومتناقضة.
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
And every year there's research done
وفي كل سنة ينجز بحث
on self-reported shyness among college students.
حول الخجل المبلغ عنه ذاتيا بين طلبة الجامعات.
And we're seeing a steady increase among males.
ونحن نرى زيادة مطردة لدى الذكور.
And this is two kinds.
وهذه نوعان.
It's a social awkwardness.
إنها الحرج الإجتماعي.
The old shyness was a fear of rejection.
الخجل السابق كان خوفا من الرفض.
It's a social awkwardness like you're a stranger in a foreign land.
إنه حرج اجتماعي وكأنك غريب في بلد أجنبي.
They don't know what to say, they don't know what to do,
لا يعرفون ماذا يقولون، لا يعرفون ماذا يفعلون،
especially one-on-one [with the] opposite sex.
خصوصا وجها لوجه مع الجنس الآخر.
They don't know the language of face contact,
لا يعرفون لغة التواصل بالوجه،
the non-verbal and verbal set of rules
مجموعة القواعد اللفظية وغير اللفظية
that enable you to comfortably talk to somebody else,
التي تسمح لك بالحديث بأريحية مع شخص آخر،
listen to somebody else.
والإستماع إلى شخص آخر.
There's something I'm developing here called social intensity syndrome,
هناك أمر أقوم بتطويره هنا يدعى متلازمة الحدة الإجتماعية،
which tries to account for why guys really prefer
والذي يحاول بيان سبب تفضيل الرجال
male bonding over female mating.
لصحبة الذكور عوضاً عن الإناث.
It turns out, from earliest childhood,
واتضح أنه منذ مراحل الطفولة الأولى،
boys, and then men,
الأولاد، ومن ثم الرجال،
prefer the company of guys --
يفضلون صحبة الذكور --
physical company.
صحبة مادية.
And there's actually a cortical arousal we're looking at,
وهناك في الواقع إستثارة نراقبها عن كثب،
because guys have been with guys
لأن تواجد الذكور مع الذكور
in teams, in clubs, in gangs, in fraternities,
في الفرق والنوادي والعصابات والأخويات
especially in the military, and then in pubs.
وخاصة في النظام العسكري وثم في الحانات.
And this peaks at Super Bowl Sunday
وهذا يصل ذروته في مباريات السوبر بول يوم الأحد
when guys would rather be in a bar with strangers,
حين يفضل الشباب التواجد في الحانة مع غرباء
watching a totally overdressed Aaron Rodgers of the Green Bay Packers,
لمشاهدة اللاعب "آرون رودجرز" من فريق "غرين باي باكرز" بملابس أكثر من اللزوم،
rather than Jennifer Lopez totally naked in the bedroom.
على التواجد مع جنيفر لوبيز عارية في غرفة النوم.
The problem is they now prefer
المشكل أنهم الآن يفضلون
[the] asynchronistic Internet world
عالم الانترنت الغير متزامن
to the spontaneous interaction
على التفاعل العفوي اللحظي
in social relationships.
في العلاقات الإجتماعية.
What are the causes? Well, it's an unintended consequence.
ما هي الأسباب؟ حسنا، إنها نتيجة غير مقصودة.
I think it's excessive Internet use in general, excessive video gaming,
أعتقد أنه عموما الإستخدام المفرط للانترنت، الإستخدام المفرط لألعاب الفيديو،
excessive new access to pornography.
الوصول الجديد المفرط للإباحية.
The problem is these are arousal addictions.
المشكل هو أن هذه إدمانات إستثارية مؤقتة.
Drug addiction, you simply want more.
في إدمان المخدرات، تريد فقط المزيد.
Arousal addiction, you want different.
في الإدمان الإستثاري تريد أمرا مختلفا.
Drugs, you want more of the same -- different.
في المخدرات، تريد المزيد من نفس الشيء -- مختلف.
So you need the novelty in order for the arousal to be sustained.
وبالتالي تحتاج إلى التجديد لاستمرار الإستثارة.
And the problem is the industry is supplying it.
والمشكل أن قطاعات الصناعة تقوم بتزويده.
Jane McGonigal told us last year
جين ماكغونيغال أخبرتنا السنة الماضية
that by the time a boy is 21,
أنه ببلوغ الولد سن ال 21،
he's played 10,000 hours of video games,
يكون قضى 100,000 ساعة في ألعاب الفيديو،
most of that in isolation.
معظم ذلك في انعزال.
As you remember, Cindy Gallop said
كما تتذكرون، سيندي غالوب قالت
men don't know the difference
الرجال لا يعرفون الفرق
between making love and doing porn.
بين ممارسة الحب والفعل الإباحي.
The average boy now watches 50 porn video clips a week.
في المتوسط يشاهد الولد الآن 50 مقطع فيديو إباحي في الأسبوع.
And there's some guy watching a hundred, obviously.
ويشاهد بعضهم 100 فيديو، كما هو واضح.
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
And the porn industry is the fastest growing industry in America --
وسوق المواد الإباحية هو أسرع القطاعات نموا في أمريكا --
15 billion annually.
15 مليار سنويا.
For every 400 movies made in Hollywood,
لكل 400 فيلم أنتجت في هوليود،
there are 11,000 now made porn videos.
هناك 11,000 فيلم إباحي منتج.
So the effect, very quickly,
وبالتالي تأثير ذلك، في عجالة،
is it's a new kind of arousal.
هو نوع جديد من الإستثارة.
Boys' brains are being digitally rewired in a totally new way
أدمغة الأولاد تتم إعادة ربطها رقميا بطريقة جديدة بالكامل
for change, novelty, excitement and constant arousal.
من أجل التغيير والتجديد والإثارة والاستثارة الدائمة.
That means they're totally out of sync in traditional classes,
ما يعني أنهم غير متزامنين تماما مع الفئات التقليدية،
which are analog, static, interactively passive.
والتي هي تناظرية وثابتة وسلبية التفاعل.
They're also totally out of sync
هم كذلك خارج التزامن
in romantic relationships,
في العلاقات الرومانسية،
which build gradually and subtly.
والتي تبنى تدريجيا وبمهارة.
So what's the solution? It's not my job.
وبالتالي ما هو الحل؟ ليست تلك وظيفتي.
I'm here to alarm. It's your job to solve.
أنا هنا لأحذركم. وظيفتكم حل المشكل.
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
(Applause)
(تصفيق)
But who should care? The only people who should care about this
لكن من يجدر به الإهتمام؟ الأشخاص الوحيدون الذين يجدر بهم أن يهتموا بهذا
is parents of boys and girls,
هم آباء الأولاد والبنات،
educators, gamers, filmmakers
المربون، صانعوا الألعاب، والسينمائيون
and women who would like a real man
والنساء اللواتي يفضلن رجلا حقيقيا
who they can talk to, who can dance,
يمكنهم الحديث معه، ويمكنه الرقص،
who can make love slowly
ويمكنه ممارسة الحب ببطء
and contribute to the evolutionary pressures
والمساهمة في الضغوط التطورية
to keep our species above banana slugs.
للإبقاء على صنفنا فوق الرخويات الموزية.
No offense to banana slug owners. Thank you.
ليست إساءة لمالكي banana slug. شكرا لكم.
(Applause)
(تصفيق)